Hi, everybody, back to Databricks free edition.
I wanted to show you something really cool with
the AI gateway when it comes to serving endpoints.
One of my favorite little features actually
is when I create a serving endpoint using clicking up here,
I'll just go to the one that I've already have.
You notice that actually I can edit
the AI gateway to block PII or ensure safety of the data.
So in other words, when there's data
like credit card numbers,
e-mail addresses, UK NI numbers,
I can actually block that stuff.
So right here, I actually have the safety there, get go.
So let me show you this is in action.
Let me go to click on the playground.
I'm going to run this, but I'm actually going to run also GPT-5.
This is with my own key to open AI to use
GPT-5 mini and try out some really quick queries.
Now, let's start off with zip code.
I'm going to type that here.
Now, this isn't PII code or anything like that.
So I'm going to go ahead and let that sucker run
and basically it'll generate some responses.
So it'll kick in and perfect.
It actually responds appropriately.
Now, in this case, they're actually both wrong.
This one says Renton, this one says Federal Way,
but it's actually for Kirkland.
But that actually has to do with OpenAI,
nothing to do with our keys itself.
But how about if I go ahead and ask the question
that actually has personally identified information
like the UK NI number?
I chuck in something like this.
You notice the one with guardrails right away,
it actually prevents you from actually sending
that particular question.
So error code, bad request.
This case, you can look through the JSON
and it tells you right away that basically no worries,
there's no hate, self-harm or any other content,
but they did notice the potentially PI information.
And that's what's listed here.
Meanwhile, my mini, it'll actually go ahead
and send the query to GPT-5 mini and OpenAI,
and it'll actually go ahead and give me this error,
which is not bad,
but it actually is sending the information to GPT-5.
Now, if you're wondering which one actually
or how this works, just refer to the instructions.
Now, notice this, the AI guardrails is in private preview,
but then it'll note right here,
personally identifiable information detection
is actually using, the AI guardrails is using Presidio.
And so if you click on this link and it'll show up here,
it'll give you all this cool information
about which ones are available, which ones accessible,
like from the USA, bank number, driver's license, UK,
includes the national insurance number, which we just sent,
and all these other pieces of information like credit card,
which is actually what we're gonna go do next, all right?
So let me go ahead,
and this is obviously a fake credit card number,
but let me go ahead and try to write that and send that now.
And then this case, again, the guardrails kicks in
and says, nope, I'm not allowed sending this information in.
Okay, and right there, you'll notice it says,
what type of credit do I have?
I'm gonna have credit for this reason,
input guardrail triggered, okay?
And this one is sending to GPT-5 mini
without the guardrails.
GPT-5 actually does go ahead and try to make sense of this.
It'll figure out that it's most likely a Visa card,
but it actually can't look up additional information.
Now, what's really cool is that with AI guardrails,
it's actually trying to protect sending the information
directly to your model,
so that way the PI information
doesn't actually ever leave your Databricks environment.
So to prove my point,
remember how I showed you back in initially
when I showed the endpoints?
Here, let me open this up just for a second, all right?
I have this, I can edit it,
and I can actually have, for example,
the plain text key, this is the setting.
Okay, I'm gonna cancel that for now, so this is enabled.
To prove my point, I'm gonna go ahead
and actually delete the key that's using, okay?
So I'm gonna revoke that key right now.
Boom, now it's gone.
I'm gonna go back to the playground.
I'm gonna send this information in, okay?
Same one, all right?
So let's see what happens.
Sorry?
All right, boom.
Now, notice that the error messages are different.
For the one with guardrails, again,
the bad request is saying
the input guardrail has been triggered, okay?
But in the case of GP5 Mini, my key,
it actually is an invalid request
because I just deleted the key.
So that's why I lost my point.
In the case of using guardrails,
we actually prevent the information
from ever even going to OpenAI in the first place.
So that's really cool.
The guardrails actually really do protect
and keep that information inside your Databricks environment.
All right, thanks very much,
and see you at the next AgentBricks demo.
♪♪♪