What's going on everybody? Welcome back
What's going on everybody? Welcome back to another video. Today we're going to
to another video. Today we're going to
to another video. Today we're going to be talking about IDP and data [music]
be talking about IDP and data [music]
be talking about IDP and data [music] bricks.
Now, as a data analyst, I spend a lot of
Now, as a data analyst, I spend a lot of my time on data collection. So, that's
my time on data collection. So, that's
my time on data collection. So, that's going to be getting the data into a
going to be getting the data into a
going to be getting the data into a usable format for other teams. And a lot
usable format for other teams. And a lot
usable format for other teams. And a lot of the times it's just in a CSV or it's
of the times it's just in a CSV or it's
of the times it's just in a CSV or it's in a database. It's really easy to use,
in a database. It's really easy to use,
in a database. It's really easy to use, but it isn't always the case. In fact, a
but it isn't always the case. In fact, a
but it isn't always the case. In fact, a lot of the data that I used to work with
lot of the data that I used to work with
lot of the data that I used to work with was in unstructured formats.
was in unstructured formats.
was in unstructured formats. Specifically, this was in healthcare
Specifically, this was in healthcare
Specifically, this was in healthcare when we were working directly with
when we were working directly with
when we were working directly with hospitals. And so, we would get doctor's
hospitals. And so, we would get doctor's
hospitals. And so, we would get doctor's notes, we would get clinician notes, we
notes, we would get clinician notes, we
notes, we would get clinician notes, we would get claims documents, and that
would get claims documents, and that
would get claims documents, and that data is not formatted in columns and
data is not formatted in columns and
data is not formatted in columns and rows. It's just free text. And I'm old
rows. It's just free text. And I'm old
rows. It's just free text. And I'm old enough to remember we would use OCR to
enough to remember we would use OCR to
enough to remember we would use OCR to extract all this data and make it usable
extract all this data and make it usable
extract all this data and make it usable and put it into columns and rows. That
and put it into columns and rows. That
and put it into columns and rows. That process was very difficult, filled with
process was very difficult, filled with
process was very difficult, filled with a ton of rules and things that would
a ton of rules and things that would
a ton of rules and things that would break down a lot, but I don't think
break down a lot, but I don't think
break down a lot, but I don't think that's the way that you should be doing
that's the way that you should be doing
that's the way that you should be doing it anymore. In fact, I've been using IDP
it anymore. In fact, I've been using IDP
it anymore. In fact, I've been using IDP in data bricks and it is amazing. So,
in data bricks and it is amazing. So,
in data bricks and it is amazing. So, let's dive into IDP and see what it is
let's dive into IDP and see what it is
let's dive into IDP and see what it is and why it is so useful. The first thing
and why it is so useful. The first thing
and why it is so useful. The first thing to look at is just what IDP actually is.
to look at is just what IDP actually is.
to look at is just what IDP actually is. It stands for intelligent document
It stands for intelligent document
It stands for intelligent document processing. It just uses AI to extract
processing. It just uses AI to extract
processing. It just uses AI to extract data and information from your
data and information from your
data and information from your documents. And I'm sure a lot of you
documents. And I'm sure a lot of you
documents. And I'm sure a lot of you guys have actually tried this at some
guys have actually tried this at some
guys have actually tried this at some point. You just pop it into Chat GBT.
point. You just pop it into Chat GBT.
point. You just pop it into Chat GBT. You say, "Hey, tell me what this
You say, "Hey, tell me what this
You say, "Hey, tell me what this document says." And it gives you kind of
document says." And it gives you kind of
document says." And it gives you kind of a right answer. I've done that myself.
a right answer. I've done that myself.
a right answer. I've done that myself. And for the most part, it's okay, but
And for the most part, it's okay, but
And for the most part, it's okay, but it's not amazing. You can even see here
it's not amazing. You can even see here
it's not amazing. You can even see here on the lefth hand side, this is a
on the lefth hand side, this is a
on the lefth hand side, this is a benchmark test for this type of process.
benchmark test for this type of process.
benchmark test for this type of process. This is going to be accuracy versus
This is going to be accuracy versus
This is going to be accuracy versus pricing. And you can see cha JBT way on
pricing. And you can see cha JBT way on
pricing. And you can see cha JBT way on the right hand side. It's going to be
the right hand side. It's going to be
the right hand side. It's going to be quite expensive for just okay accuracy
quite expensive for just okay accuracy
quite expensive for just okay accuracy right around 76 77%. You'll notice
right around 76 77%. You'll notice
right around 76 77%. You'll notice though data bricks is in the top left
though data bricks is in the top left
though data bricks is in the top left which is kind of exactly where you want
which is kind of exactly where you want
which is kind of exactly where you want to be. You want it to be the most
to be. You want it to be the most
to be. You want it to be the most accurate for the lowest price and data
accurate for the lowest price and data
accurate for the lowest price and data bicks does that. Now why does IDP matter
bicks does that. Now why does IDP matter
bicks does that. Now why does IDP matter at all? And this goes back to the exact
at all? And this goes back to the exact
at all? And this goes back to the exact thing I was talking about at the very
thing I was talking about at the very
thing I was talking about at the very beginning, which is a lot of data is not
beginning, which is a lot of data is not
beginning, which is a lot of data is not actually stored in databases and columns
actually stored in databases and columns
actually stored in databases and columns and rows. It's just free text. It's
and rows. It's just free text. It's
and rows. It's just free text. It's unstructured data. There is a ton of
unstructured data. There is a ton of
unstructured data. There is a ton of really important data in these
really important data in these
really important data in these unstructured data types and just these
unstructured data types and just these
unstructured data types and just these free text and documents that are sitting
free text and documents that are sitting
free text and documents that are sitting out there that people want to be able to
out there that people want to be able to
out there that people want to be able to use, but they just can't in its current
use, but they just can't in its current
use, but they just can't in its current state. Something that makes IDP really
state. Something that makes IDP really
state. Something that makes IDP really useful is that it is taking into context
useful is that it is taking into context
useful is that it is taking into context the document that you're processing. So,
the document that you're processing. So,
the document that you're processing. So, it isn't fully rules-based, which OCR
it isn't fully rules-based, which OCR
it isn't fully rules-based, which OCR pretty much was. When I was back on my
pretty much was. When I was back on my
pretty much was. When I was back on my data collection team, we had a lot of
data collection team, we had a lot of
data collection team, we had a lot of pipelines that had OCR in it. And I
pipelines that had OCR in it. And I
pipelines that had OCR in it. And I would say at least once a week, they
would say at least once a week, they
would say at least once a week, they would break. They would just break down
would break. They would just break down
would break. They would just break down because the structure changed or
because the structure changed or
because the structure changed or something changed in the documents or
something changed in the documents or
something changed in the documents or the document file type changed. It just
the document file type changed. It just
the document file type changed. It just would happen all the time. This is what
would happen all the time. This is what
would happen all the time. This is what makes IDP really powerful because it
makes IDP really powerful because it
makes IDP really powerful because it isn't completely rules-based like OCR
isn't completely rules-based like OCR
isn't completely rules-based like OCR was because if anything changed within
was because if anything changed within
was because if anything changed within that document, it just broke. it just
that document, it just broke. it just
that document, it just broke. it just immediately stopped working and it was
immediately stopped working and it was
immediately stopped working and it was horrible and we had to fix things all
horrible and we had to fix things all
horrible and we had to fix things all the time. But with IDP, it's really
the time. But with IDP, it's really
the time. But with IDP, it's really flexible to the document that you're
flexible to the document that you're
flexible to the document that you're actually using. For example, on this
actually using. For example, on this
actually using. For example, on this right hand side, this is just a PDF
right hand side, this is just a PDF
right hand side, this is just a PDF document. This is some image that
document. This is some image that
document. This is some image that somebody put out there, but it isn't
somebody put out there, but it isn't
somebody put out there, but it isn't sitting in columns and rows. There's
sitting in columns and rows. There's
sitting in columns and rows. There's free text on the lefthand side. There's
free text on the lefthand side. There's
free text on the lefthand side. There's columns and rows on the right hand side.
columns and rows on the right hand side.
columns and rows on the right hand side. Now, this data might be really useful
Now, this data might be really useful
Now, this data might be really useful that you want to extract even the data
that you want to extract even the data
that you want to extract even the data in the free text on the lefth hand side.
in the free text on the lefth hand side.
in the free text on the lefth hand side. With IDP, you'll be able to write pretty
With IDP, you'll be able to write pretty
With IDP, you'll be able to write pretty simple code to extract the data in the
simple code to extract the data in the
simple code to extract the data in the free text. And it's very easy to extract
free text. And it's very easy to extract
free text. And it's very easy to extract the data on the right hand side. And if
the data on the right hand side. And if
the data on the right hand side. And if things change, maybe they flip sides or
things change, maybe they flip sides or
things change, maybe they flip sides or more data is added or there's more free
more data is added or there's more free
more data is added or there's more free text on the lefth hand side, it's still
text on the lefth hand side, it's still
text on the lefth hand side, it's still going to be really flexible with that
going to be really flexible with that
going to be really flexible with that data type. And in future lessons, we are
data type. And in future lessons, we are
data type. And in future lessons, we are going to deep dive into this. I'm going
going to deep dive into this. I'm going
going to deep dive into this. I'm going to actually show you how to extract data
to actually show you how to extract data
to actually show you how to extract data just like this. So, let's take a look at
just like this. So, let's take a look at
just like this. So, let's take a look at the difference between traditional
the difference between traditional
the difference between traditional processing and IDP. Now, traditional
processing and IDP. Now, traditional
processing and IDP. Now, traditional processing is the one that I kind of
processing is the one that I kind of
processing is the one that I kind of grew up with or the one that I've used
grew up with or the one that I've used
grew up with or the one that I've used the most because this is just what we
the most because this is just what we
the most because this is just what we had when we were doing this type of
had when we were doing this type of
had when we were doing this type of work. This is going to be using OCR,
work. This is going to be using OCR,
work. This is going to be using OCR, which stands for optical character
which stands for optical character
which stands for optical character recognition. This is what I used and
recognition. This is what I used and
recognition. This is what I used and basically everybody else used for
basically everybody else used for
basically everybody else used for unstructured data. And you would set
unstructured data. And you would set
unstructured data. And you would set custom rules for each document that you
custom rules for each document that you
custom rules for each document that you were working with. There were so many
were working with. There were so many
were working with. There were so many different tools and templates that you
different tools and templates that you
different tools and templates that you can use, and those were really helpful.
can use, and those were really helpful.
can use, and those were really helpful. But again, things would break fairly
But again, things would break fairly
But again, things would break fairly easily, and so it was a lot of
easily, and so it was a lot of
easily, and so it was a lot of maintenance to actually keep up with
maintenance to actually keep up with
maintenance to actually keep up with these pipelines. The most frustrating
these pipelines. The most frustrating
these pipelines. The most frustrating thing about using this was when a
thing about using this was when a
thing about using this was when a customer would not tell you that they're
customer would not tell you that they're
customer would not tell you that they're going to be changing a format to a PDF
going to be changing a format to a PDF
going to be changing a format to a PDF or whatever document they were sending
or whatever document they were sending
or whatever document they were sending you. They would just change it and you
you. They would just change it and you
you. They would just change it and you wouldn't find out until like a week
wouldn't find out until like a week
wouldn't find out until like a week later or 2 weeks later when the data
later or 2 weeks later when the data
later or 2 weeks later when the data just wasn't coming in anymore. Now, it
just wasn't coming in anymore. Now, it
just wasn't coming in anymore. Now, it was still worth maintaining. It was
was still worth maintaining. It was
was still worth maintaining. It was still worth using those OCR systems
still worth using those OCR systems
still worth using those OCR systems because we would get a lot of really
because we would get a lot of really
because we would get a lot of really good data out of it, but it wasn't 100%
good data out of it, but it wasn't 100%
good data out of it, but it wasn't 100% accurate. We had several data quality
accurate. We had several data quality
accurate. We had several data quality analysts who would be on our team who
analysts who would be on our team who
analysts who would be on our team who would manually check a lot of these
would manually check a lot of these
would manually check a lot of these things and run tons of queries and tons
things and run tons of queries and tons
things and run tons of queries and tons of code to make sure that the data is
of code to make sure that the data is
of code to make sure that the data is really accurate. Traditional processing
really accurate. Traditional processing
really accurate. Traditional processing with OCR is not a bad system. It's just
with OCR is not a bad system. It's just
with OCR is not a bad system. It's just a lot of work. Now with IDP, we're going
a lot of work. Now with IDP, we're going
a lot of work. Now with IDP, we're going to be using an AI agent-based system. So
to be using an AI agent-based system. So
to be using an AI agent-based system. So when it processes your document, it's
when it processes your document, it's
when it processes your document, it's going to understand the layout and the
going to understand the layout and the
going to understand the layout and the context of your document without you
context of your document without you
context of your document without you having to create the rules for it. One
having to create the rules for it. One
having to create the rules for it. One of the best things about this is just
of the best things about this is just
of the best things about this is just that it doesn't break very easily. It's
that it doesn't break very easily. It's
that it doesn't break very easily. It's really hard because it's so flexible.
really hard because it's so flexible.
really hard because it's so flexible. it's really hard to actually get it to
it's really hard to actually get it to
it's really hard to actually get it to break. So with traditional OCR, if you
break. So with traditional OCR, if you
break. So with traditional OCR, if you change it from a PDF into like a DOCX or
change it from a PDF into like a DOCX or
change it from a PDF into like a DOCX or just a Word document, it's going to
just a Word document, it's going to
just a Word document, it's going to break, right? It's looking for a
break, right? It's looking for a
break, right? It's looking for a specific file type. But with IDP, it's
specific file type. But with IDP, it's
specific file type. But with IDP, it's just going to really easily, flexibly
just going to really easily, flexibly
just going to really easily, flexibly change from one document type to
change from one document type to
change from one document type to another. IDP has a ton of built-in
another. IDP has a ton of built-in
another. IDP has a ton of built-in functions, and those are what we're
functions, and those are what we're
functions, and those are what we're going to be looking at in the next
going to be looking at in the next
going to be looking at in the next several lessons. They have a bunch of
several lessons. They have a bunch of
several lessons. They have a bunch of built-in functions that do a lot of the
built-in functions that do a lot of the
built-in functions that do a lot of the heavy lifting for you. You basically
heavy lifting for you. You basically
heavy lifting for you. You basically just need to point at it. You need to
just need to point at it. You need to
just need to point at it. You need to say here's what you should be looking
say here's what you should be looking
say here's what you should be looking for and it's going to do most of the
for and it's going to do most of the
for and it's going to do most of the work for you. So there aren't a ton of
work for you. So there aren't a ton of
work for you. So there aren't a ton of custom rules that you need to be
custom rules that you need to be
custom rules that you need to be creating. Now in just a second we're
creating. Now in just a second we're
creating. Now in just a second we're going to talk about how we actually use
going to talk about how we actually use
going to talk about how we actually use IDP in data bricks but this is just a
IDP in data bricks but this is just a
IDP in data bricks but this is just a visual for you to see kind of what it
visual for you to see kind of what it
visual for you to see kind of what it looks like for that transformation. It's
looks like for that transformation. It's
looks like for that transformation. It's super simplified but it can take a raw
super simplified but it can take a raw
super simplified but it can take a raw PDF and in that PDF it could be free
PDF and in that PDF it could be free
PDF and in that PDF it could be free text, it could be columns and rows.
text, it could be columns and rows.
text, it could be columns and rows. We'll look at both in the next lessons.
We'll look at both in the next lessons.
We'll look at both in the next lessons. But you're going to parse out that data.
But you're going to parse out that data.
But you're going to parse out that data. You're going to use the IDP process
You're going to use the IDP process
You're going to use the IDP process which we're going to look at in just a
which we're going to look at in just a
which we're going to look at in just a sec. and it's going to put it into
sec. and it's going to put it into
sec. and it's going to put it into columns and rows to make that data
columns and rows to make that data
columns and rows to make that data usable. This is what I would say 95% of
usable. This is what I would say 95% of
usable. This is what I would say 95% of people want when they have these PDF
people want when they have these PDF
people want when they have these PDF documents that they want to use. They
documents that they want to use. They
documents that they want to use. They want to just have it in columns and rows
want to just have it in columns and rows
want to just have it in columns and rows that they can query off the data and
that they can query off the data and
that they can query off the data and they can actually use the data. And so
they can actually use the data. And so
they can actually use the data. And so how do you do that within data bricks? I
how do you do that within data bricks? I
how do you do that within data bricks? I had mentioned those AI functions and
had mentioned those AI functions and
had mentioned those AI functions and that's what you're going to use. You're
that's what you're going to use. You're
that's what you're going to use. You're going to use it for parsing, extracting
going to use it for parsing, extracting
going to use it for parsing, extracting and then classifying your data. If you
and then classifying your data. If you
and then classifying your data. If you know how to use those functions as well
know how to use those functions as well
know how to use those functions as well as just some basic SQL or Python because
as just some basic SQL or Python because
as just some basic SQL or Python because you can use either one, you can use IDP
you can use either one, you can use IDP
you can use either one, you can use IDP within data bricks to do this entire
within data bricks to do this entire
within data bricks to do this entire process. I personally like using SQL.
process. I personally like using SQL.
process. I personally like using SQL. That's what we're going to use in the
That's what we're going to use in the
That's what we're going to use in the next several lessons. But it's just as
next several lessons. But it's just as
next several lessons. But it's just as easy to use Python in the notebooks as
easy to use Python in the notebooks as
easy to use Python in the notebooks as well. One of my favorite things about
well. One of my favorite things about
well. One of my favorite things about using IDP and data bricks and I've used
using IDP and data bricks and I've used
using IDP and data bricks and I've used a lot of tools. I've used a lot of
a lot of tools. I've used a lot of
a lot of tools. I've used a lot of processes. One of my favorite things is
processes. One of my favorite things is
processes. One of my favorite things is that it's all in one place. This isn't
that it's all in one place. This isn't
that it's all in one place. This isn't some complex pipeline that uses six or
some complex pipeline that uses six or
some complex pipeline that uses six or seven different tools. It's all within
seven different tools. It's all within
seven different tools. It's all within data bricks. And so you have your raw
data bricks. And so you have your raw
data bricks. And so you have your raw data, your raw PDF files sitting in the
data, your raw PDF files sitting in the
data, your raw PDF files sitting in the catalog. And then once you process it,
catalog. And then once you process it,
catalog. And then once you process it, you're going to have your structured
you're going to have your structured
you're going to have your structured data sitting right next to it. And so
data sitting right next to it. And so
data sitting right next to it. And so you have your raw data, you have your
you have your raw data, you have your
you have your raw data, you have your code, and you have your structured
code, and you have your structured
code, and you have your structured output all in one place. And so it makes
output all in one place. And so it makes
output all in one place. And so it makes it really easy to actually do quality
it really easy to actually do quality
it really easy to actually do quality checks on your data. And if you've ever
checks on your data. And if you've ever
checks on your data. And if you've ever run quality checks on your data before,
run quality checks on your data before,
run quality checks on your data before, which you absolutely should be doing,
which you absolutely should be doing,
which you absolutely should be doing, when it's all spread out, it's all in
when it's all spread out, it's all in
when it's all spread out, it's all in these different systems, it is very,
these different systems, it is very,
these different systems, it is very, very tedious. And so actually having it
very tedious. And so actually having it
very tedious. And so actually having it all in one place makes it 10 times
all in one place makes it 10 times
all in one place makes it 10 times easier. Now in the next several lessons
easier. Now in the next several lessons
easier. Now in the next several lessons we're going to be diving into these
we're going to be diving into these
we're going to be diving into these functions of parsing, extracting and
functions of parsing, extracting and
functions of parsing, extracting and classifying our data. And then at the
classifying our data. And then at the
classifying our data. And then at the very end we'll have an end to end
very end we'll have an end to end
very end we'll have an end to end process where you can build out an
process where you can build out an
process where you can build out an entire process where you have your raw
entire process where you have your raw
entire process where you have your raw documents. We're going to process all of
documents. We're going to process all of
documents. We're going to process all of them. It could be 50, could be 100
them. It could be 50, could be 100
them. It could be 50, could be 100 documents. We're going to process it
documents. We're going to process it
documents. We're going to process it into structured data. I'm going to show
into structured data. I'm going to show
into structured data. I'm going to show you that it's actually quite easy and
you that it's actually quite easy and
you that it's actually quite easy and extremely accurate. I am a huge data
extremely accurate. I am a huge data
extremely accurate. I am a huge data collection nerd. This is like something
collection nerd. This is like something
collection nerd. This is like something I really enjoy. So, I can't wait to get
I really enjoy. So, I can't wait to get
I really enjoy. So, I can't wait to get hands-on, actually start writing out all
hands-on, actually start writing out all
hands-on, actually start writing out all the code and showing you how this works.
the code and showing you how this works.
the code and showing you how this works. We're going to be using the Data Bricks
We're going to be using the Data Bricks
We're going to be using the Data Bricks free edition for all this. So, all this
free edition for all this. So, all this
free edition for all this. So, all this is completely free to use. All you have
is completely free to use. All you have
is completely free to use. All you have to do is click on the link in the
to do is click on the link in the
to do is click on the link in the description. Go ahead and create an
description. Go ahead and create an
description. Go ahead and create an account and follow along in the next
account and follow along in the next
account and follow along in the next several lessons. I hope this was really
several lessons. I hope this was really
several lessons. I hope this was really helpful. If it was, be sure to like and
helpful. If it was, be sure to like and
helpful. If it was, be sure to like and subscribe, and I will see you in the
subscribe, and I will see you in the
subscribe, and I will see you in the next video.
next video.
next video. [music]