AI agents are here for enterprises, and they hold massive potential.
These tools that can reason, decide, and act are the talk of companies everywhere.
But getting agents to production is still too hard.
Why aren't agents everywhere?
It's because enterprise AI agents are hard to get right.
Many of them just don't work.
And the ones that do?
They're not always accurate.
They force choices and don't let you choose the best combination of models for the job.
And they create risk, forcing you to send your critical data to external AI models.
That's why thousands of organizations around the globe have partnered with Databricks to
adopt a different approach.
At Databricks, we've pioneered a better way to build enterprise AI agents,
tailoring them automatically to your data and use case to provide real value.
Banks are using multi-agent systems to securely review investment theses and generate investment
memos, saving 200,000 man-hours and generating $250 million in value.
In energy, teams are combining real-time grid, meter, and weather data to predict potential
disruptions and restore power 25% faster for customers, saving $18 million in annual outage costs.
And in healthcare and life sciences, they're predicting how drug molecules impact gene
expression, accelerating the understanding of disease biology to design new cures.
Databricks gives you the highest accuracy by using research-backed techniques to measure
and tune agents that continuously improve without needing to be rebuilt.
So you can get more agents to production and have more success with AI.
Visit the Databricks website to learn more.